Hello friends welcome back to the new
video so my name is Vinod Kumar and in
today's video I am going to tell you whether
you
can claim your insurance without RC and license or not so
I got a lot of such questions
so I thought of
making a complete video about it to explain in detail whether
you can claim your insurance without RC and license or
not so let's start the video for those
who don't know first of all I will
tell you the big thing, well almost everyone will know so let me
tell everyone that RC
and license
is a very important document if you guys ride a bike so
like you know that the
driving license which we
also call diesel in short form, so with that
thing you mean by that you have bought a new bike,
you need it to buy a new bike,
okay because without DL in
some places you don't
get the bike, okay and
your insurance gets renewed through RC, so
both of these are important documents
If you do
not have both these documents which are going to be with the bike, then it is better that you do
not ride the bike.
Now let us talk about our most important thing which is whether
you can make a claim without DL and RC or not. So,
first of all I will tell you that
if you have any one of these documents i.e. DL and RC, then
you can make a claim. If
you do not have any of these two documents, then
you cannot make a claim. You
can make a claim on one condition, understand that if you
have RC and license and both of them are
lost, if one of the two is lost, then it happens
in one, if both of them are
lost, if it means it is lost,
as it is said that it means you either
dropped it somewhere or someone stole it, something like this happens, then
you can do it in that case. There is
a scheme of Aadhar in this,
you can do this through that, so for this also,
wherever you have lost your DL, that
means report and everything etc.  All those
copies are required,
after that you can claim your bike insurance without license and without
RC. The
second tip that
I will tell you is that
whenever you have taken insurance,
what terms and conditions does your insurance policy
give in it and on the basis of what are the terms and
conditions, you can
claim your bike insurance
without driving license and without RC. Well,
99.9% of the time it happens that you will be asked for RC license compulsorily at the time
of insurance.
If it is not there many times, then
in that case you can claim insurance without deal and without
RC. So,
without RC and without license, that is, the
scheme that is added is
through the insurance company, in that
you have to pay some higher premium
and when will you get the claim, there is such a
system, so for that you should
talk to your insurance company that
if you do not have RC and license, then
what will be the percentage in it and
how will it happen?  According to me, whatever I
told you that whatever you people will
add on to the RC, there is some
percentage increase or decrease in it.
Some people had another question that if the
bike is in my father's name, then can I
claim it. Now, as it happens,
some people buy a bike, like I also
bought a bike in the beginning, then at that time the bike was in
my father's name, okay, and I had a
bike and whatever is there with it, that is, the
RC etc., all were in his name and
I had a license, okay, what will happen in this case, in
this case, if your bike meets with an
accident or something happens, then
in this case, you, that is, the person in whose name the
bike is, will get the insurance claim, you will
not get an advice, yes, it can happen that
if your bike gets damaged, then the
RC etc. documents of your father's name will be attached, that is,
without a license, it is
not necessary to have documents and
you can make your insurance claim only with the RC and his documents, so
I  I have told you this thing that if you have
your father's document then there is no
problem in that, only in case of accident
you will face a lot of problem in getting the claim,
if the
bike is not in your name and you are riding it and
if something happens to you, then I am
good, you will like the video
and whatever information you wanted you would have got
through this video, so I will
meet you in the next video, till then
bye-bye, if you people want to know whether
you
get one year insurance with the new bike or 2 years
or 3 years, what is the catch or discrepancy in 5 years insurance,
you will get to know all this through this video,
so let's go, we will meet you in the next video, till then
bye-bye